# Jared Coleman

https://www.jaredraycoleman.com

SUMMARY & SKILLS

I have a broad interest in computer science. My research interests include distributed computing, the internet of things (IoT), blockchain, mobile robotics, discrete mathematics, computational geometry, and game theory.

Languages: Python, C/C++, Java, JavaScript

University of Southern California

Technologies/Frameworks: Docker, Tendermint, Git, React, Gitpod

**Graduate Courses**: Advanced Algorithm Design, Distributed Systems, Formal Verification, Randomized Algorithms, Theory of Computation, High-Performance Computing, Programming Languages, Operating Systems

#### EDUCATION

# Ph.D. in Computer Science; GPA: 4.0 California State University, Long Beach Master of Science in Computer Science; GPA: 4.0 Bachelor of Science in Computer Science; GPA: 3.6 Aug 2018 – May 2020 Aug 2013 – May 2018

#### EXPERIENCE

| The Aerospace Corporation               | El Segundo, CA        |
|---|-----------------------|
| Casual Member of the Technical Staff    | Aug 2020 – Present    |
| Member of the Technical Staff           | $Mar\ 2020-Aug\ 2020$ |
| Associate Member of the Technical Staff | Sep 2018 – Mar 2020   |
| Intern                                  | $Jan\ 2018-Aug\ 2018$ |

- Design software that helps Aerospace rapidly develop scalable, modular, and efficient analyses for launch vehicle verification in simulation, day-of-launch, and post-flight environments.

# **CSULB Research Foundation**

Long Beach, CA

Los Angeles, CA

Student Research Assistant

Mar 2017 - May 2018

jaredraycoleman@gmail.com

- Developed software and simulations for systems of cooperative robots.

# Publications

## Graph Convolutional Network-based Scheduler for Distributing Computation in the IoRT

Jared Coleman, Mehrdad Kiamari, Lillian Clark, Daniel D'Souza, Bhaskar Krishnamachari MILCOM 2023 WS-7 - Workshop On The Internet Of Things For Adversarial Environments

# Delivery to Safety with Two Cooperating Robots

Jared Coleman, Evangelos Kranakis, Danny Krizanc, Oscar Morales-Ponce

SOFSEM 2023 - International Conference on Current Trends in Theory and Practice of Computer Science

## The Snow Plow Problem: Perpetual Maintenance by Mobile Agents on the Line

Jared Coleman, Oscar Morales-Ponce

ICDCN 2023 - International Conference on Distributed Computing and Networking

#### Line Search for an Oblivious Moving Target

Jared Coleman, Evangelos Kranakis, Danny Krizanc, Oscar Morales-Ponce OPODIS 2022 - International Conference on Principles of Distributed Systems

#### Multi-Objective Network Synthesis for Dispersed Computing in Tactical Environments

Jared Coleman, Eugenio Grippo, Bhaskar Krishnamachari, Gunjan Verma

SPIE Defense + Commercial Sensing 2022

# Network Synthesis for Tactical Environments: Scenario, Challenges, and Opportunities

Tzanis Anevlavis, Jonathan Bunton, Jared Coleman, Mine Dogan, Eugenio Grippo, Abel Souza, Christina Fragouli Bhaskar Krishnamachari, Matthew Maness, Karl Olson, Prashant Shenoy, Paulo Tabuada, Gunjan Verma efense + Commercial Sensing 2022

# Robotic Sorting on the Grid

Jared Coleman, Oscar Morales-Ponce

ICDCN 2022 - 23rd International Conference on Distributed Computing and Networking

#### Message Delivery in the Plane by Robots with Different Speeds

Jared Coleman, Evangelos Kranakis, Oscar Morales-Ponce, Danny Krizanc SSS 2021 - 23rd International Symposium on Stabilization, Safety, and Security of Distributed Systems

# The Pony Express Communication Problem

Jared Coleman, Evangelos Kranakis, Oscar Morales-Ponce, Danny Krizanc In Proceedings IWOCA 2021 - 32nd International Workshop on Combinatorial Algorithms

# Minimizing The Maximum Distance Traveled To Form Patterns With Systems of Mobile Robots

Jared Coleman, Evangelos Kranakis, Oscar Morales-Ponce, Jorge Urrutia, Birgit Vogtenhuber In proceedings CCCG 2020, 32nd Canadian Conference on Computational Geometry, August 5-7, 2020

#### PROJECTS

# GCN-Turtlebot (github.com/ANRGUSC/gcnschedule-turtlenet)

GCN-based Scheduler for Distributing Computation in the Internet of Robotic Things

First-place winner: 2nd Student Designgit ad Competition on Networked Computing on the Edge at CPS IoT Week 2022

# Secure IIoT

Autonomous Networks Research Group & Chevron

Using blockchain technology to secure industrial IoT systems

## Kubishi (kubishi.com)

An online dictionary and encyclopedia for Owens Valley Painte language and culture

2020

#### Aerocube @ The Beach

CSULB & The Aerospace Corporation

Distributed robotics systems for space - a proof of concept

2017